https://www.sunywcc.edu/legal/

Legal
Westchester Community College’s Privacy Policy
Westchester Community College respects the privacy of all visitors to our web site and does not provide any of our personal information to third parties without your permission, unless compelled by law or court order to do so, and does not sell any personal information to third parties for purposes of marketing, advertising, or promotion. However, the college reserves the right to share data with our marketing partners for marketing reporting purposes and for remarketing and retargeting college messages to individuals who visit our website or contact the college.
Please review the following Privacy Policy to understand what information is being collected and how it will be used.
Endorsements and Accuracy of Content
Westchester Community College provides access to distributed and local networked resources as a service to the campus community and the community at large. The availability of networked information via Westchester Community College’s information services does not constitute endorsement of the content or accuracy of that information by Westchester Community College. Sections linked to this site are maintained by independent groups and individuals. The views expressed in these home pages are those of the page authors; comments regarding those pages should be directed to them.
Equal Opportunity Institution
Westchester Community College is an equal opportunity institution and adheres to the policy that no person on the basis of race, color, sex, religion, national origin, age, disability, sexual orientation, or genetic information is excluded from or is subject to discrimination in any program or activity.
Commitment to Privacy
At Westchester Community College, we are committed to protecting your privacy and making it easier for individuals and businesses to interact with Westchester Community College. We recognize that it is critical for individuals and businesses to be confident that their privacy is protected when they visit www.sunywcc.edu. You can travel through most of www.sunywcc.edu without giving us any information about yourself. Sometimes we do need information to provide services that you request, and this commitment of privacy explains our online information practices.
Voluntary Communication
Westchester Community College does not collect any personal information about you unless you provide that information voluntarily by sending an e-mail or by completing Westchester Community College online forms.
This policy is consistent with the provisions of the following:
Internet Security and Privacy Act
Freedom of Information Law
Personal Privacy Protection Law
Collected Information
When visiting www.sunywcc.edu, Westchester Community College automatically collects and stores the following information about your visit:
The Internet Protocol address of the computer that accessed our web site
The type of browser, its version and the operating system on which that browser is running
The web page from which the user accessed the current web page
The date and time of the user’s request
The pages that were visited and the amount of time spent at each page
None of the above-mentioned information is deemed to constitute personal information by the Internet Privacy and Security Act. The information that is collected automatically is used to improve www.sunywcc.edu’s content and to help Westchester Community College understand how users are interacting with its website. This information is collected for statistical analysis and to determine what information is of most and least interest to our users. The information is not collected for commercial marketing purposes and Westchester Community College is not authorized to sell or otherwise disclose the information collected from www.sunywcc.edu for commercial marketing purposes.
Information Collected When You E-mail or Complete a Transaction
During your visit to www.sunywcc.edu you may send an e-mail to the Westchester Community College. Your e-mail address and the contents of your message will be collected. The information collected is not limited to text characters and may include audio, video, and graphic information formats included in the message. Your e-mail address and the information included in your message will be used to respond to you, to address issues you identify, to improve this website, or to forward your message to another Westchester Community College campus for appropriate action. Your e-mail address is not collected for commercial purposes and Westchester Community College is not authorized to sell or otherwise disclose your e-mail address for commercial purposes.
During your visit to www.sunywcc.edu you may communicate with us online. The information collected by Westchester Community College, including personal information volunteered by you in completing the communication, is used by Westchester Community College and may be disclosed by Westchester Community College for those purposes that may be reasonably ascertained from the nature and terms of the transaction in which the information was submitted.
Aggregate Information
We may take your personal information and make it non-personally identifiable, either by combining it with information about other individuals (aggregating your information with information about other individuals), or by removing characteristics (such as your name) that make the information personally identifiable to you (i.e., de-personalizing your information).  This can include usage information and/or information that is not connected to personal information.  Given the nature of this information, no restrictions apply under this Privacy Policy on our right to aggregate or de-personalize your personal information, and we may use and share in any way with third parties the resulting non-personally identifiable information.
Information regarding minors (children under the age of 13)
Westchester Community College does not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13 or create profiles of children under the age of 13. Users are cautioned, however, that the collection of personal information submitted in an e-mail will be treated as though it was submitted by an adult, and may, unless exempted from access by federal or State law, be subject to public access.
Disclosure of Information Collected Through This Website
The collection of information through www.sunywcc.edu and the disclosure of that information are subject to the provisions of the Internet Security and Privacy Act. Westchester Community College will only collect personal information through www.sunywcc.edu or disclose personal information collected through www.sunywcc.edu if the user has consented to the collection or disclosure of such personal information. The voluntary disclosure of personal information to Westchester Community College by the user, constitutes consent to the collection and disclosure of the information by Westchester Community College for the purposes for which the user disclosed the information to Westchester Community College.
However, Westchester Community College may collect or disclose personal information without consent if the collection or disclosure is:
necessary to perform the statutory duties of Westchester Community College, or necessary for Westchester Community College to operate a program authorized by law, or authorized by state or federal statute or regulation;
made pursuant to a court order or by law;
for the purpose of validating the identity of the user; or
of information to be used solely for statistical purposes that is in a form that cannot be used to identify any particular person.
Further, the disclosure of information, including personal information, collected through www.sunywcc.edu, is subject to the provisions of the Freedom of Information Law and the Personal Privacy Protection Law.
Unauthorized Access (hacking)
Westchester Community College may disclose personal information to federal or state law enforcement authorities to enforce its rights against unauthorized access or attempted unauthorized access to Westchester Community College’s information technology assets.
Retention of Information Collected Through This Web Site
The information collected through www.sunywcc.edu is retained by Westchester Community College in accordance with the records retention and disposition requirements of the New York State Arts & Cultural Affairs Law. In general, the Internet services logs of Westchester Community College, comprising electronic files or automated logs created to monitor access and use of Agency services provided through www.sunywcc.edu, are retained indefinitely. Information concerning these records retention and disposition schedules may be obtained through the Internet privacy policy contact listed in this policy.
Access to and Correction of Personal Information Collected
Any user may submit a request to Westchester Community College ‘s privacy compliance officer to determine whether personal information pertaining to that user has been collected through www.sunywcc.edu. Any such request shall be made in writing and must be accompanied by reasonable proof of identity of the user. Reasonable proof of identity may include verification of a signature, inclusion of an identifier generally known only to the user, or similar appropriate identification. The address of the privacy compliance officer is:
Patrick Hennessey
Director, Marketing and Communications
Westchester Community College
75 Grasslands Road
Valhalla, New York 10595
The privacy compliance officer shall, within five (5) business days of the receipt of a proper request, provide access to the personal information; deny access in writing, explaining the reasons therefore; or acknowledge the receipt of the request in writing, stating the approximate date when the request will be granted or denied, which date shall not be more than thirty (30) days from the date of the acknowledgment.
In the event that Westchester Community College has collected personal information pertaining to a user through www.sunywcc.edu and that information is to be provided to the user pursuant to the user’s request, the privacy compliance officer shall inform the user of his or her right to request that the personal information be amended or corrected under the procedures set forth in section 95 of the Public Officers Law.
Confidentiality and Integrity of Personal Information Collected
Westchester Community College is strongly committed to protecting personal information collected through www.sunywcc.edu against unauthorized access, use or disclosure. Consequently, Westchester Community College limits employee access to personal information collected through www.sunywcc.edu to only those employees who need access to the information in the performance of their official duties. Employees who have access to this information follow appropriate procedures in connection with any disclosures of personal information.
In addition, Westchester Community College has implemented procedures to safeguard the integrity of its information technology assets, including, but not limited to, authentication, authorization, monitoring, auditing, and encryption. These security procedures have been integrated into the design, implementation, and day-to-day operations of www.sunywcc.edu as part of our continuing commitment to the security of electronic content as well as the electronic transmission of information.
For web site security purposes and to maintain the availability of www.sunywcc.edu for all users, Westchester Community College employs software to monitor traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information or otherwise damage www.sunywcc.edu.
Cookies
Cookies are small pieces of information that are stored by the user’s browser on the hard drive of your computer. www.sunywcc.edu does not use cookies.
Use of E-Mail
In spite of the good intentions of the college to respect the privacy of individuals, it should be understood that it is impossible to assure the privacy of e-mail. Not only may email be sent to someone other than the intended recipient (either through mis-addressing or forwarding), but email sent as plain text may also be intercepted as it travels over the network
The use of College resources, including computing and networking equipment and services, purchased with College funds, are intended for college business. While it is not the intention of the College to actively monitor communications or files stored or transmitted on College systems or devices, individuals must understand that under certain circumstances they may not have a right to privacy to such information. Such circumstances include but are not limited to:
compliance with legal requirements or process;
as part of an investigation of a suspected violation of law
regulation or College policy; to maintain the integrity of the College’s computing systems.
Freedom of Information Requests
Under the “Freedom of Information Act (FOIA)”, except as otherwise provided by federal law or state statute, all records maintained or kept on file are considered public records and are subject to inspection by members of the public. As a member of the College community, your email and any information collected in the course of visiting a web site are considered public records and may be subject to Freedom of Information disclosure. In some cases email messages about students may fall under the FERPA definition of ‘education records’ and therefore be subject to the provisions of FERPA regarding the release of the information and the student’s right to inspect and review the information.
Disclaimer
The Westchester Community College web site has many links to other web sites. When you link to another site, you are no longer on the Westchester Community College web site and this privacy policy will not apply. When you link to another web site, you are subject to the privacy policy of that new site.
Neither Westchester Community College, nor any agency, officer, or employee of Westchester Community College warrants the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of any information published by this system, nor endorses any content, viewpoints, products, or services linked from this system, and shall not be held liable for any losses caused by reliance on the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of such information. Portions of such information may be incorrect or not current. Any person or entity that relies on any information obtained from this system does so at their own risk.
Westchester Community College reserves the right to revise and update this privacy policy at any time by posting such revised privacy policy on the Westchester Community College home page.
Internal, college-wide emails are to be concerned with college business. We do not condone the dissemination of political or personal messages through such college-wide emails unless specifically approved by the Office of Marketing and Communications. In certain cases, if the messages are deemed to be connected to specific college events, clubs, or college-sponsored enterprises, such messages will be approved. All such messages must be approved in advance by the Office of College Community Relations.
Wireless Statement
One of the college’s goals is to transition to a completely wireless main campus in Valhalla. We have begun this effort, but be aware that on most areas of the campus you will be accessing a network which has been secured with firewall protection.  Since such protection does not guarantee the security of your personal information, use your own discretion.
Definitions
The following definitions apply to, and appear in italics, in this policy:
Personal information: For purposes of this policy, “personal information” means any information concerning a natural person which, because of name, number, symbol, mark, or other identifier, can be used to identify that natural person.
User: shall have the meaning set forth in subdivision 8 of section 202 of the State Technology Law.
Blog policy
Westchester Community College blogs have been created for use by members of the greater community, including but not restricted to prospective and current students blogging from any location, Westchester County residents, college alumni, faculty, staff, and administrators. The purpose of the blogs is to facilitate communication to and from the college and its greater “community,” which includes all of the above. Commentary and opinion are most welcome.
We will only post comments from bloggers 13 years or older that relate to topics concerning the college and its community. We understand there will be exceptions regarding subject matter , but the following will be removed by Westchester Community College blog authors and editors, and repeat offenders will be banned for:
Potentially libelous comments.
Vulgar, racist, sexist comments.
Personal attacks.
Plagiarized material.
Private information published without consent.
Material related to gambling.
Items that could damage other computers.
Commercials, soliciting for personal gain, or spam.
Profanity or objectionable images.
The college reserves the right not to post comments or images. Please remember that the views and opinions expressed by bloggers are strictly those of the authors . Also understand that  the contents of blog entries may create lasting consequences, so be respectful and professional in your postings. By participating in any college blogs, you are responsible for your comments and you agree not to represent yourself as another individual.
Social Networking Policy
Westchester Community College’s social networking site pages have been created for use by members of the greater community, including but not restricted to prospective and current students blogging from any location, Westchester County residents, college alumni, faculty, staff, and administrators. The purpose of the sites is to facilitate communication to and from the college and its greater “community,” which includes all of the above. Commentary and opinion are most welcome.
We encourage comments from bloggers 13 years or older relating to topics concerning the college and its community. We understand there will be exceptions regarding subject matter, but the following will be removed by Westchester Community College’s social networking site administrators, and repeat offenders will be banned for:
Potentially libelous comments.
Vulgar, racist, sexist, or comments pertaining to violence.
Personal attacks.
Plagiarized material.
Private information published without consent.
Profanity.
Material related to gambling.
Items that could damage other computers.
Commercials, soliciting for personal gain, or spam.
The college reserves the right to delete comments. Please remember that the views and opinions expressed by fans/friends are strictly those of the authors. Also understand that the contents of your postings may create lasting consequences, so be respectful and professional. By participating, you are responsible for your comments and you agree not to represent yourself as another individual.
If you are a student at the college, please understand that you assume an obligation to conduct yourself in a manner compatible with the institution’s academic standards, general policies, and the Student Code of Conduct. This includes comments made on social media. Behavior which adversely affects a student’s responsible membership in the academic community shall result in appropriate disciplinary action. Also, please note that this is not the forum to discuss opinions on individual students, faculty or staff. Remember, when using social media, do not share personal information which you do not want to be made public. Please email us at info@sunywcc.edu if you want to communicate with the college administration in a private manner.
Contact Information
For questions regarding this Internet privacy policy, please contact our privacy officer via e-mail at info@sunywcc.edu or by regular mail at:
Institutional Review Board (IRB)
Jobs/Human Resources
Office of Institutional Research, Planning, and Effectiveness
Educational Opportunity Center (WEOC)
Valhalla (Main Campus)
Maps & Directions
